Lynda Foster

lyndabrf@gmail.com | Phone | Portfolio | LinkedIn | Github | Burbank, CA

SUMMARY

Computer Science graduate with a background in Finance and client-facing roles, eager to leverage my engineering skills in a professional setting; academic and project experience includes 2 years object-oriented programming, 1 year .NET/C# web/API development, and 2 years SQL development and database administration.

SKILLS

- Languages: C# | JavaScript
- Frameworks: ASP.NET Core (MVC Web App/API, Class Library) | Entity Framework Core
- Databases: SQL | PostgreSQL
- Cloud Application Platforms: GitHub | Heroku | Splunk | Azure
- Other: HTML | CSS | Regex | Bootstrap | Postman | Swagger

PROJECTS | Portfolio

Ifost42/brailleAPI

- .NET REST API, manages a database of ascii braille special symbols as defined by the International Council on English Braille.
- Swagger documentation follows Open API Specification standards.

Ifost42/blog | Website

- ASP.NET Full stack web application, used as a knowledge base of .NET(C#) coding and web
 development articles.
- Implements identity/role based access and rendering to limit article permissions to the owner while allowing users to leave comments.
- Google SMTP email service verifies user registration and forwards contact form submissions to the owner.
- Code-first approach using Entity Framework Core and PostgreSQL.

Ifost42/Franchise | Website

- ASP.NET Full stack web application that evaluates the coverage health of a franchise by determining which locations (in a provided csv file) are farthest apart.
- Explores Kruskal's Minimum Spanning Tree to filter locations that can pass through other locations.
- Leveraged Unit tests (TDD) to manage scope changes as the app evolved over time.

EXPERIENCE

Benefit Plans Inc, Los Angeles, CA | Employer Services Analyst | 01/2019 - Present

- Developed, implemented, and maintained digital operational procedures that manage \$100M+ in monthly contribution payments to pre-taxed PH&W (pension, health, and welfare) benefit accounts.
- Produced the training knowledge base for the Employer Services department which expedited the onboarding of new employees.

Lynda Foster

 Eliminated 40% of the processing time needed to reconcile discrepancies by automating the conversion of raw data to readable format using Excel macros and PowerShell scripts.

B'nai Hayim, Sherman Oaks, CA | Technical Coordinator | 04/2018 – 09/2019

- Established a system for financial reporting, database management, and website maintenance to facilitate the merging of two separate organizations.
- Created a knowledge base to train non-technical staff to independently update their website/database, maintain financial records, reconcile bank accounts, and create monthly financial reports using Quickbooks Online.
- Normalized csv data into 1st normal form for migration into an established relational database.

VOLUNTEER

Recovering From Religion, Kansas City, KS | Web Developer | 06/2022 - Present

- Utilize GitHub to track issues, review pull requests, resolve merge conflicts.
- Gather requirements from end users to ensure new features are efficiently implemented and maintained.
- Participate in weekly stand-ups with 6 other developers to maintain, manage, and extend the organization's main management and chat web applications in an agile setting.
- Review, analyze, develop, and modify existing code written Typescript (Node and React).

CERTIFICATIONS

Microsoft Certified: Azure Fundamentals (in progress) | Splunk Core Power User | ITIL Foundation in IT Service Management | Oracle Database SQL Certified Associate 1Z0-071

EDUCATION

BSc in Computer Science | Western Governors University, Salt Lake City, UT
Technologies: C++, Java, Python, MySQL, Machine Learning, Web Development